<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Goblin Finder</string>
    <string name="btnString">Back</string>
    <string name="cotterell_intro">You have found a Julatrell Goblin!</string>
    <string name="cotterell_appearance">
        Appearance: These goblins have adapted to take on human form through many years of evolution. What tells them apart from normal humans are the following. Those who change into the female form will usually have a derp like default face. Males tend to be blind and develop very small arms.
    </string>
    <string name="cotterell_society">
        Society: Given they are shapeshifters, it’s hard to tell how they interact with their own race and how they live day by day. What we do know is that these creatures tend to live in colder climates and have been sighted in the New England area of the United States of America in states like New York, Virginia and Maine.
    </string>
    <string name="cotterell_ecology">
        Ecology: It is assumed the Julatrells live their days like normal humans so we have no data of what they do on a daily basis.
    </string>
    <string name="jenkin_intro">You have found a Jenkfru Goblin!</string>
    <string name="jenkin_appearance">
        Appearance: Cloaking themselves as a pudgy human in the prime of their life, the jenkfru goblin roams the lands of New York for the finest of jenk items.
    </string>
    <string name="jenkin_society">
        Society: Given they are shapeshifters, it’s hard to tell how they interact with their own race and how they live day by day. What we do know is these goblins tend to live in colder climates and have been sighted in the New England area of the United States of America in states like New York
    </string>
    <string name="jenkin_ecology">
        Ecology: It is assumed the Jenkfrus live their days like humans so we have no data of what they do on a daily basis.
    </string>
    <string name="bakemono_intro">You have found a Bakemono Goblin!</string>
    <string name="bakemono_appearance_pt.1">
        Bakemono live in tribes of 20 and 80 persons, so if you see one, there probably more around. These large communities are ruled by a sacred shaman known as an Oni. Despite this sense of unity, Bakemono lack the loyalty to pledge themselves to one clan and would often leave and join other factions impulsively. Like most goblins, internecine combat was common, and when not fighting among themselves, they will conduct raids on nearby human settlements or attack travelers.
    </string>
    <string name="bakemono_appearance_pt.2">
        Often known as savages, these ferocious brutes prefer to ambush their target and are usually seen recklessly charging into battle. Rarely, if ever, do the Bakemono have their own weapons or armor, as these goblins carry the arms from their previous victims. What equipment they did possess was often neglected, causing them to wield dull and rusty weapons in battle. When it comes to wearing armor on their misshapen bodies, they will create an unorganized patchwork of different pieces of mail and plate, woven together with rope and string.
    </string>
    <string name="bakemono_ecology">
        Being the natural born savages they are, Bakemono are often seen as a ruthless animals who see anything that moves as a potential threat. Over the years they have treated mankind with such animosity that they will attack any human settlement with no hesitation or forethought. They’re dominantly carnivores as they like to eat their meat raw.
    </string>
    <string name="batiri_intro">You have found a Batiri Goblin</string>
    <string name="batiri_appearance">
        Dwelling in primarily jungle environments, their green skin allows them to camouflage in their natural environment. They will often be dressed in rags as their more prestigious warriors or chieftains display themselves in dinosaur-hide breastplates and helmets.
    </string>
    <string name="batiri_society">
        Each clan will usually have a population between 25 and 200 goblins, all under the influence of an ordained chieftain. These creatures have always chosen a nomadic lifestyles in their forested domain. There have been accounts of Batiri huts constructed in various parts of their domain. In spite of their pilgrimage like personality, these habitats were made to provide temporary shelter and protection from the elements. These dwellings would often be abandoned, only to be occupied by a roaming clan for a night.
    </string>
    <string name="batiri_ecology">
        Batiri are nocturnal creatures by instinct and hunt in the middle of the night. They use the secrecy and eerie atmosphere of the jungle to stalk their prey. While most use crude shortbows and poorly made spears, some of their most experienced warriors will wield stolen weapons from human settlements or fallen adventurers. Some have claimed the Batiri are cannibals since they will eat the flesh of any animal they come across. However, this is not the case as it’s considered immoral for Batiri to eat their own kind, even if they hailed from an enemy clan. Committing such an act would be punished by death. 
    </string>

</resources>
